Name

glCompressedTexImage2D — specify a two-dimensional texture image in a compressed format

C Specification

void glCompressedTexImage2D( | GLenum   | target,
  | GLint   | level,
  | GLenum   | internalformat,
  | GLsizei   | width,
  | GLsizei   | height,
  | GLint   | border,
  | GLsizei   | imageSize,
  | const GLvoid *   | data);

Parameters

target

Specifies the target texture. Must be GL_TEXTURE_2D, GL_PROXY_TEXTURE_2D, GL_TEXTURE_1D_ARRAY, GL_PROXY_TEXTURE_1D_ARRAY, GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP_POSITIVE_X, GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP_NEGATIVE_X, GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP_POSITIVE_Y, GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP_NEGATIVE_Y, GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP_POSITIVE_Z, GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP_NEGATIVE_Z, or GL_PROXY_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP.

level

Specifies the level-of-detail number. Level 0 is the base image level. Level n is the nth mipmap reduction image.

internalformat

Specifies the format of the compressed image data stored at address data.

width

Specifies the width of the texture image. All implementations support 2D texture images that are at least 64 texels wide and cube-mapped texture images that are at least 16 texels wide.

height

Specifies the height of the texture image. All implementations support 2D texture images that are at least 64 texels high and cube-mapped texture images that are at least 16 texels high.

border

This value must be 0.

imageSize

Specifies the number of unsigned bytes of image data starting at the address specified by data.

data

Specifies a pointer to the compressed image data in memory.

Description

Texturing allows elements of an image array to be read by shaders.

glCompressedTexImage2D loads a previously defined, and retrieved, compressed two-dimensional texture image if target is GL_TEXTURE_2D, or one of the cube map faces such as GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP_POSITIVE_X. (see glTexImage2D).

If target is GL_TEXTURE_1D_ARRAY, data is treated as an array of compressed 1D textures.

If target is GL_PROXY_TEXTURE_2D, GL_PROXY_TEXTURE_1D_ARRAY or GL_PROXY_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP, no data is read from data, but all of the texture image state is recalculated, checked for consistency, and checked against the implementation's capabilities. If the implementation cannot handle a texture of the requested texture size, it sets all of the image state to 0, but does not generate an error (see glGetError). To query for an entire mipmap array, use an image array level greater than or equal to 1.

internalformat must be a known compressed image format (such as GL_RGTC) or an extension-specified compressed-texture format. When a texture is loaded with glTexImage2D using a generic compressed texture format (e.g., GL_COMPRESSED_RGB), the GL selects from one of its extensions supporting compressed textures. In order to load the compressed texture image using glCompressedTexImage2D, query the compressed texture image's size and format using glGetTexLevelParameter.

If a non-zero named buffer object is bound to the GL_PIXEL_UNPACK_BUFFER target (see glBindBuffer) while a texture image is specified, data is treated as a byte offset into the buffer object's data store.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if internalformat is not one of the generic compressed internal formats: GL_COMPRESSED_RED, GL_COMPRESSED_RG, GL_COMPRESSED_RGB, GL_COMPRESSED_RGBA. GL_COMPRESSED_SRGB, or GL_COMPRESSED_SRGB_ALPHA.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if imageSize is not consistent with the format, dimensions, and contents of the specified compressed image data.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if border is not 0.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if parameter combinations are not supported by the specific compressed internal format as specified in the specific texture compression extension.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if a non-zero buffer object name is bound to the GL_PIXEL_UNPACK_BUFFER target and the buffer object's data store is currently mapped.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if a non-zero buffer object name is bound to the GL_PIXEL_UNPACK_BUFFER target and the data would be unpacked from the buffer object such that the memory reads required would exceed the data store size.

Undefined results, including abnormal program termination, are generated if data is not encoded in a manner consistent with the extension specification defining the internal compression format.

Associated Gets

glGetCompressedTexImage

glGet with argument GL_TEXTURE_COMPRESSED

glGet with argument GL_PIXEL_UNPACK_BUFFER_BINDING

glGetTexLevelParameter with arguments GL_TEXTURE_INTERNAL_FORMAT and GL_TEXTURE_COMPRESSED_IMAGE_SIZE

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glActiveTexture, glCompressedTexImage1D, glCompressedTexImage3D, glCompressedTexSubImage1D, glCompressedTexSubImage2D, glCompressedTexSubImage3D, glCopyTexImage1D, glCopyTexSubImage1D, glCopyTexSubImage2D, glCopyTexSubImage3D, glPixelStore, glTexImage2D, glTexImage3D, glTexSubImage1D, glTexSubImage2D, glTexSubImage3D, glTexParameter

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glDrawArrays — render primitives from array data

C Specification

void glDrawArrays( | GLenum   | mode,
  | GLint   | first,
  | GLsizei   | count);

Parameters

mode

Specifies what kind of primitives to render. Symbolic constants GL_POINTS, GL_LINE_STRIP, GL_LINE_LOOP, GL_LINES, GL_LINE_STRIP_ADJACENCY, GL_LINES_ADJACENCY, GL_TRIANGLE_STRIP, GL_TRIANGLE_FAN, GL_TRIANGLES, GL_TRIANGLE_STRIP_ADJACENCY and GL_TRIANGLES_ADJACENCY are accepted.

first

Specifies the starting index in the enabled arrays.

count

Specifies the number of indices to be rendered.

Description

glDrawArrays specifies multiple geometric primitives with very few subroutine calls. Instead of calling a GL procedure to pass each individual vertex, normal, texture coordinate, edge flag, or color, you can prespecify separate arrays of vertices, normals, and colors and use them to construct a sequence of primitives with a single call to glDrawArrays.

When glDrawArrays is called, it uses count sequential elements from each enabled array to construct a sequence of geometric primitives, beginning with element first. mode specifies what kind of primitives are constructed and how the array elements construct those primitives.

Vertex attributes that are modified by glDrawArrays have an unspecified value after glDrawArrays returns. Attributes that aren't modified remain well defined.

Notes

GL_LINE_STRIP_ADJACENCY, GL_LINES_ADJACENCY, GL_TRIANGLE_STRIP_ADJACENCY and GL_TRIANGLES_ADJACENCY are available only if the GL version is 3.2 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if mode is not an accepted value.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if count is negative.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if a non-zero buffer object name is bound to an enabled array and the buffer object's data store is currently mapped.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if a geometry shader is active and mode is incompatible with the input primitive type of the geometry shader in the currently installed program object.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glDrawArraysInstanced, glDrawElements, glDrawRangeElements,

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glDrawBuffers — Specifies a list of color buffers to be drawn into

C Specification

void glDrawBuffers( | GLsizei   | n,
  | const GLenum *  | bufs);

Parameters

n

Specifies the number of buffers in bufs.

bufs

Points to an array of symbolic constants specifying the buffers into which fragment colors or data values will be written.

Description

glDrawBuffers defines an array of buffers into which outputs from the fragment shader data will be written. If a fragment shader writes a value to one or more user defined output variables, then the value of each variable will be written into the buffer specified at a location within bufs corresponding to the location assigned to that user defined output. The draw buffer used for user defined outputs assigned to locations greater than or equal to n is implicitly set to GL_NONE and any data written to such an output is discarded.

The symbolic constants contained in bufs may be any of the following:

GL_NONE

The fragment shader output value is not written into any color buffer.

GL_FRONT_LEFT

The fragment shader output value is written into the front left color buffer.

GL_FRONT_RIGHT

The fragment shader output value is written into the front right color buffer.

GL_BACK_LEFT

The fragment shader output value is written into the back left color buffer.

GL_BACK_RIGHT

The fragment shader output value is written into the back right color buffer.

GL_COLOR_ATTACHMENTn

The fragment shader output value is written into the nth color attachment of the current framebuffer. n may range from 0 to the value of GL_MAX_COLOR_ATTACHMENTS.

Except for GL_NONE, the preceding symbolic constants may not appear more than once in bufs. The maximum number of draw buffers supported is implementation dependent and can be queried by calling glGet with the argument GL_MAX_DRAW_BUFFERS.

Notes

The symbolic constants GL_FRONT, GL_BACK, GL_LEFT, GL_RIGHT, and GL_FRONT_AND_BACK are not allowed in the bufs array since they may refer to multiple buffers.

If a fragment shader does not write to a user defined output variable, the values of the fragment colors following shader execution are undefined. For each fragment generated in this situation, a different value may be written into each of the buffers specified by bufs.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if one of the values in bufs is not an accepted value.

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if the GL is bound to the default framebuffer and one or more of the values in bufs is one of the GL_COLOR_ATTACHMENTn tokens.

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if the GL is bound to a framebuffer object and one or more of the values in bufs is anything other than GL_NONE or one of the GL_COLOR_ATTACHMENTn tokens.

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if n is less than 0.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if a symbolic constant other than GL_NONE appears more than once in bufs.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if any of the entries in bufs (other than GL_NONE ) indicates a color buffer that does not exist in the current GL context.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if n is greater than GL_MAX_DRAW_BUFFERS.

Associated Gets

glGet with argument GL_MAX_DRAW_BUFFERS

glGet with argument GL_DRAW_BUFFERi where i indicates the number of the draw buffer whose value is to be queried

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glBlendFunc, glColorMask, glDrawBuffers, glLogicOp, glReadBuffer

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. https://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glDrawElements — render primitives from array data

C Specification

void glDrawElements( | GLenum   | mode,
  | GLsizei   | count,
  | GLenum   | type,
  | const GLvoid *   | indices);

Parameters

mode

Specifies what kind of primitives to render. Symbolic constants GL_POINTS, GL_LINE_STRIP, GL_LINE_LOOP, GL_LINES, GL_LINE_STRIP_ADJACENCY, GL_LINES_ADJACENCY, GL_TRIANGLE_STRIP, GL_TRIANGLE_FAN, GL_TRIANGLES, GL_TRIANGLE_STRIP_ADJACENCY and GL_TRIANGLES_ADJACENCY are accepted.

count

Specifies the number of elements to be rendered.

type

Specifies the type of the values in indices. Must be one of GL_UNSIGNED_BYTE, GL_UNSIGNED_SHORT, or GL_UNSIGNED_INT.

indices

Specifies an offset of the first index in the array in the data store of the buffer currently bound to the GL_ELEMENT_ARRAY_BUFFER target.

Description

glDrawElements specifies multiple geometric primitives with very few subroutine calls. Instead of calling a GL function to pass each individual vertex, normal, texture coordinate, edge flag, or color, you can prespecify separate arrays of vertices, normals, and so on, and use them to construct a sequence of primitives with a single call to glDrawElements.

When glDrawElements is called, it uses count sequential elements from an enabled array, starting at indices to construct a sequence of geometric primitives. mode specifies what kind of primitives are constructed and how the array elements construct these primitives. If more than one array is enabled, each is used.

Vertex attributes that are modified by glDrawElements have an unspecified value after glDrawElements returns. Attributes that aren't modified maintain their previous values.

Notes

GL_LINE_STRIP_ADJACENCY, GL_LINES_ADJACENCY, GL_TRIANGLE_STRIP_ADJACENCY and GL_TRIANGLES_ADJACENCY are available only if the GL version is 3.2 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if mode is not an accepted value.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if count is negative.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if a geometry shader is active and mode is incompatible with the input primitive type of the geometry shader in the currently installed program object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if a non-zero buffer object name is bound to an enabled array or the element array and the buffer object's data store is currently mapped.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glDrawArrays, glDrawElementsInstanced, glDrawElementsBaseVertex, glDrawRangeElements

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glFenceSync — create a new sync object and insert it into the GL command stream

C Specification

GLsync glFenceSync( | GLenum condition,
  | GLbitfield flags);

Parameters

condition

Specifies the condition that must be met to set the sync object's state to signaled. condition must be GL_SYNC_GPU_COMMANDS_COMPLETE.

flags

Specifies a bitwise combination of flags controlling the behavior of the sync object. No flags are presently defined for this operation and flags must be zero.[1]

Description

glFenceSync creates a new fence sync object, inserts a fence command into the GL command stream and associates it with that sync object, and returns a non-zero name corresponding to the sync object.

When the specified condition of the sync object is satisfied by the fence command, the sync object is signaled by the GL, causing any glWaitSync, glClientWaitSync commands blocking in sync to unblock. No other state is affected by glFenceSync or by the execution of the associated fence command.

condition must be GL_SYNC_GPU_COMMANDS_COMPLETE. This condition is satisfied by completion of the fence command corresponding to the sync object and all preceding commands in the same command stream. The sync object will not be signaled until all effects from these commands on GL client and server state and the framebuffer are fully realized. Note that completion of the fence command occurs once the state of the corresponding sync object has been changed, but commands waiting on that sync object may not be unblocked until after the fence command completes.

Notes

glFenceSync is only supported if the GL version is 3.2 or greater, or if the ARB_sync extension is supported.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if condition is not GL_SYNC_GPU_COMMANDS_COMPLETE.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if flags is not zero.

Additionally, if glFenceSync fails, it will return zero.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glDeleteSync, glGetSync, glWaitSync, glClientWaitSync

Copyright

Copyright © 2010 Khronos Group. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. https://opencontent.org/openpub/.

[1] flags is a placeholder for anticipated future extensions of fence sync object capabilities.

Name

glFrontFace — define front- and back-facing polygons

C Specification

void glFrontFace( | GLenum mode);

Parameters

mode

Specifies the orientation of front-facing polygons. GL_CW and GL_CCW are accepted. The initial value is GL_CCW.

Description

In a scene composed entirely of opaque closed surfaces, back-facing polygons are never visible. Eliminating these invisible polygons has the obvious benefit of speeding up the rendering of the image. To enable and disable elimination of back-facing polygons, call glEnable and glDisable with argument GL_CULL_FACE.

The projection of a polygon to window coordinates is said to have clockwise winding if an imaginary object following the path from its first vertex, its second vertex, and so on, to its last vertex, and finally back to its first vertex, moves in a clockwise direction about the interior of the polygon. The polygon's winding is said to be counterclockwise if the imaginary object following the same path moves in a counterclockwise direction about the interior of the polygon. glFrontFace specifies whether polygons with clockwise winding in window coordinates, or counterclockwise winding in window coordinates, are taken to be front-facing. Passing GL_CCW to mode selects counterclockwise polygons as front-facing; GL_CW selects clockwise polygons as front-facing. By default, counterclockwise polygons are taken to be front-facing.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if mode is not an accepted value.

Associated Gets

glGet with argument GL_FRONT_FACE

See Also

glCullFace,

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glGetActiveUniformBlockName — retrieve the name of an active uniform block

C Specification

void glGetActiveUniformBlockName( | GLuint program,
  | GLuint uniformBlockIndex,
  | GLsizei bufSize,
  | GLsizei *length,
  | GLchar *uniformBlockName);

Parameters

program

Specifies the name of a program containing the uniform block.

uniformBlockIndex

Specifies the index of the uniform block within program.

bufSize

Specifies the size of the buffer addressed by uniformBlockName.

length

Specifies the address of a variable to receive the number of characters that were written to uniformBlockName.

uniformBlockName

Specifies the address an array of characters to receive the name of the uniform block at uniformBlockIndex.

Description

glGetActiveUniformBlockName retrieves the name of the active uniform block at uniformBlockIndex within program.

program must be the name of a program object for which the command glLinkProgram must have been called in the past, although it is not required that glLinkProgram must have succeeded. The link could have failed because the number of active uniforms exceeded the limit.

uniformBlockIndex is an active uniform block index of program, and must be less than the value of GL_ACTIVE_UNIFORM_BLOCKS.

Upon success, the name of the uniform block identified by unifomBlockIndex is returned into uniformBlockName. The name is nul-terminated. The actual number of characters written into uniformBlockName, excluding the nul terminator, is returned in length. If length is NULL, no length is returned.

bufSize contains the maximum number of characters (including the nul terminator) that will be written into uniformBlockName.

If an error occurs, nothing will be written to uniformBlockName or length.

Errors

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not the name of a program object for which glLinkProgram has been called in the past.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if uniformBlockIndex is greater than or equal to the value of GL_ACTIVE_UNIFORM_BLOCKS or is not the index of an active uniform block in program.

Notes

glGetActiveUniformBlockName is available only if the GL version is 3.1 or greater.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glGetActiveUniformBlock, glGetUniformBlockIndex

Copyright

Copyright © 2010 Khronos Group. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. https://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glGetShaderSource — Returns the source code string from a shader object

C Specification

void glGetShaderSource( | GLuint   | shader,
  | GLsizei   | bufSize,
  | GLsizei *  | length,
  | GLchar *  | source);

Parameters

shader

Specifies the shader object to be queried.

bufSize

Specifies the size of the character buffer for storing the returned source code string.

length

Returns the length of the string returned in source (excluding the null terminator).

source

Specifies an array of characters that is used to return the source code string.

Description

glGetShaderSource returns the concatenation of the source code strings from the shader object specified by shader. The source code strings for a shader object are the result of a previous call to glShaderSource. The string returned by the function will be null terminated.

glGetShaderSource returns in source as much of the source code string as it can, up to a maximum of bufSize characters. The number of characters actually returned, excluding the null termination character, is specified by length. If the length of the returned string is not required, a value of NULL can be passed in the length argument. The size of the buffer required to store the returned source code string can be obtained by calling glGetShader with the value GL_SHADER_SOURCE_LENGTH.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if shader is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if shader is not a shader object.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if bufSize is less than 0.

Associated Gets

glGetShader with argument GL_SHADER_SOURCE_LENGTH

glIsShader

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glCreateShader, glShaderSource

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. https://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glGetUniformBlockIndex — retrieve the index of a named uniform block

C Specification

GLuint glGetUniformBlockIndex( | GLuint program,
  | const GLchar *uniformBlockName);

Parameters

program

Specifies the name of a program containing the uniform block.

uniformBlockName

Specifies the address an array of characters to containing the name of the uniform block whose index to retrieve.

Description

glGetUniformBlockIndex retrieves the index of a uniform block within program.

program must be the name of a program object for which the command glLinkProgram must have been called in the past, although it is not required that glLinkProgram must have succeeded. The link could have failed because the number of active uniforms exceeded the limit.

uniformBlockName must contain a nul-terminated string specifying the name of the uniform block.

glGetUniformBlockIndex returns the uniform block index for the uniform block named uniformBlockName of program. If uniformBlockName does not identify an active uniform block of program, glGetUniformBlockIndex returns the special identifier, GL_INVALID_INDEX. Indices of the active uniform blocks of a program are assigned in consecutive order, beginning with zero.

Errors

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not the name of a program object for which glLinkProgram has been called in the past.

Notes

glGetUniformBlockIndex is available only if the GL version is 3.1 or greater.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glGetActiveUniformBlockName, glGetActiveUniformBlock, glLinkProgram

Copyright

Copyright © 2010 Khronos Group. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. https://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glLinkProgram — Links a program object

C Specification

void glLinkProgram(GLuint program);

Parameters

program

Specifies the handle of the program object to be linked.

Description

glLinkProgram links the program object specified by program. If any shader objects of type GL_VERTEX_SHADER are attached to program, they will be used to create an executable that will run on the programmable vertex processor. If any shader objects of type GL_GEOMETRY_SHADER are attached to program, they will be used to create an executable that will run on the programmable geometry processor. If any shader objects of type GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER are attached to program, they will be used to create an executable that will run on the programmable fragment processor.

The status of the link operation will be stored as part of the program object's state. This value will be set to GL_TRUE if the program object was linked without errors and is ready for use, and GL_FALSE otherwise. It can be queried by calling glGetProgram with arguments program and GL_LINK_STATUS.

As a result of a successful link operation, all active user-defined uniform variables belonging to program will be initialized to 0, and each of the program object's active uniform variables will be assigned a location that can be queried by calling glGetUniformLocation. Also, any active user-defined attribute variables that have not been bound to a generic vertex attribute index will be bound to one at this time.

Linking of a program object can fail for a number of reasons as specified in the OpenGL Shading Language Specification. The following lists some of the conditions that will cause a link error.

The number of active attribute variables supported by the implementation has been exceeded.

The storage limit for uniform variables has been exceeded.

The number of active uniform variables supported by the implementation has been exceeded.

The main function is missing for the vertex, geometry or fragment shader.

A varying variable actually used in the fragment shader is not declared in the same way (or is not declared at all) in the vertex shader, or geometry shader shader if present.

A reference to a function or variable name is unresolved.

A shared global is declared with two different types or two different initial values.

One or more of the attached shader objects has not been successfully compiled.

Binding a generic attribute matrix caused some rows of the matrix to fall outside the allowed maximum of GL_MAX_VERTEX_ATTRIBS.

Not enough contiguous vertex attribute slots could be found to bind attribute matrices.

The program object contains objects to form a fragment shader but does not contain objects to form a vertex shader.

The program object contains objects to form a geometry shader but does not contain objects to form a vertex shader.

The program object contains objects to form a geometry shader and the input primitive type, output primitive type, or maximum output vertex count is not specified in any compiled geometry shader object.

The program object contains objects to form a geometry shader and the input primitive type, output primitive type, or maximum output vertex count is specified differently in multiple geometry shader objects.

The number of active outputs in the fragment shader is greater than the value of GL_MAX_DRAW_BUFFERS.

The program has an active output assigned to a location greater than or equal to the value of GL_MAX_DUAL_SOURCE_DRAW_BUFFERS and has an active output assigned an index greater than or equal to one.

More than one varying out variable is bound to the same number and index.

The explicit binding assigments do not leave enough space for the linker to automatically assign a location for a varying out array, which requires multiple contiguous locations.

The count specified by glTransformFeedbackVaryings is non-zero, but the program object has no vertex or geometry shader.

Any variable name specified to glTransformFeedbackVaryings in the varyings array is not declared as an output in the vertex shader (or the geometry shader, if active).

Any two entries in the varyings array given glTransformFeedbackVaryings specify the same varying variable.

The total number of components to capture in any transform feedback varying variable is greater than the constant GL_MAX_TRANSFORM_FEEDBACK_SEPARATE_COMPONENTS and the buffer mode is GL_SEPARATE_ATTRIBS.

When a program object has been successfully linked, the program object can be made part of current state by calling glUseProgram. Whether or not the link operation was successful, the program object's information log will be overwritten. The information log can be retrieved by calling glGetProgramInfoLog.

glLinkProgram will also install the generated executables as part of the current rendering state if the link operation was successful and the specified program object is already currently in use as a result of a previous call to glUseProgram. If the program object currently in use is relinked unsuccessfully, its link status will be set to GL_FALSE , but the executables and associated state will remain part of the current state until a subsequent call to glUseProgram removes it from use. After it is removed from use, it cannot be made part of current state until it has been successfully relinked.

If program contains shader objects of type GL_VERTEX_SHADER, and optionally of type GL_GEOMETRY_SHADER, but does not contain shader objects of type GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER, the vertex shader executable will be installed on the programmable vertex processor, the geometry shader executable, if present, will be installed on the programmable geometry processor, but no executable will be installed on the fragment processor. The results of rasterizing primitives with such a program will be undefined.

The program object's information log is updated and the program is generated at the time of the link operation. After the link operation, applications are free to modify attached shader objects, compile attached shader objects, detach shader objects, delete shader objects, and attach additional shader objects. None of these operations affects the information log or the program that is part of the program object.

Notes

If the link operation is unsuccessful, any information about a previous link operation on program is lost (i.e., a failed link does not restore the old state of program ). Certain information can still be retrieved from program even after an unsuccessful link operation. See for instance glGetActiveAttrib and glGetActiveUniform.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if program is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is the currently active program object and transform feedback mode is active.

Associated Gets

glGet with the argument GL_CURRENT_PROGRAM

glGetActiveAttrib with argument program and the index of an active attribute variable

glGetActiveUniform with argument program and the index of an active uniform variable

glGetAttachedShaders with argument program

glGetAttribLocation with argument program and an attribute variable name

glGetProgram with arguments program and GL_LINK_STATUS

glGetProgramInfoLog with argument program

glGetUniform with argument program and a uniform variable location

glGetUniformLocation with argument program and a uniform variable name

glIsProgram

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glAttachShader, glBindAttribLocation, glCompileShader, glCreateProgram, glDeleteProgram, glDetachShader, glUniform, glUseProgram, glValidateProgram

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. Copyright © 2010 Khronos Group. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. https://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glMultiDrawArrays — render multiple sets of primitives from array data

C Specification

void glMultiDrawArrays( | GLenum   | mode,
  | const GLint *   | first,
  | const GLsizei *   | count,
  | GLsizei   | primcount);

Parameters

mode

Specifies what kind of primitives to render. Symbolic constants GL_POINTS, GL_LINE_STRIP, GL_LINE_LOOP, GL_LINES, GL_LINE_STRIP_ADJACENCY, GL_LINES_ADJACENCY, GL_TRIANGLE_STRIP, GL_TRIANGLE_FAN, GL_TRIANGLES, GL_TRIANGLE_STRIP_ADJACENCY and GL_TRIANGLES_ADJACENCY are accepted.

first

Points to an array of starting indices in the enabled arrays.

count

Points to an array of the number of indices to be rendered.

primcount

Specifies the size of the first and count

Description

glMultiDrawArrays specifies multiple sets of geometric primitives with very few subroutine calls. Instead of calling a GL procedure to pass each individual vertex, normal, texture coordinate, edge flag, or color, you can prespecify separate arrays of vertices, normals, and colors and use them to construct a sequence of primitives with a single call to glMultiDrawArrays.

glMultiDrawArrays behaves identically to glDrawArrays except that primcount separate ranges of elements are specified instead.

When glMultiDrawArrays is called, it uses count sequential elements from each enabled array to construct a sequence of geometric primitives, beginning with element first. mode specifies what kind of primitives are constructed, and how the array elements construct those primitives.

Vertex attributes that are modified by glMultiDrawArrays have an unspecified value after glMultiDrawArrays returns. Attributes that aren't modified remain well defined.

Notes

GL_LINE_STRIP_ADJACENCY, GL_LINES_ADJACENCY, GL_TRIANGLE_STRIP_ADJACENCY and GL_TRIANGLES_ADJACENCY are available only if the GL version is 3.2 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if mode is not an accepted value.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if primcount is negative.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if a non-zero buffer object name is bound to an enabled array and the buffer object's data store is currently mapped.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glDrawElements, glDrawRangeElements

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glPrimitiveRestartIndex — specify the primitive restart index

C Specification

void glPrimitiveRestartIndex( | GLuint index);

Parameters

index

Specifies the value to be interpreted as the primitive restart index.

Description

glPrimitiveRestartIndex specifies a vertex array element that is treated specially when primitive restarting is enabled. This is known as the primitive restart index.

When one of the Draw* commands transfers a set of generic attribute array elements to the GL, if the index within the vertex arrays corresponding to that set is equal to the primitive restart index, then the GL does not process those elements as a vertex. Instead, it is as if the drawing command ended with the immediately preceding transfer, and another drawing command is immediately started with the same parameters, but only transferring the immediately following element through the end of the originally specified elements.

When either glDrawElementsBaseVertex, glDrawElementsInstancedBaseVertex or glMultiDrawElementsBaseVertex is used, the primitive restart comparison occurs before the basevertex offset is added to the array index.

Notes

glPrimitiveRestartIndex is available only if the GL version is 3.1 or greater.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glDrawArrays, glDrawElements, glDrawElementsBaseVertex, glDrawElementsInstancedBaseVertex

Copyright

Copyright © 2010 Khronos Group. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. https://opencontent.org/openpub/.